American Civil Liberties Union Records: Subgroup 2, Audiovisual Materials Series, 1947-1995: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 6, Audio-Visual materials, 1930-1995; 70 boxes, 1 folder
  - Audio Tapes, 1961 March-1989; portion of 8 boxes
    - Audio Cassette Tapes, 1976-1989; portion of 5 boxes
      - Biennial Conference, 1989; 1 box
        - National and Affiliate Report, dates not examined; 27; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - Public Education on the Bill of Rights, dates not examined; 28; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - Racism on the Rise, dates not examined; 29; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - Civil Liberties and the Drug Crisis, dates not examined; 30 A-B; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - The Constitution and Economic Rights, dates not examined; 31; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - First Voting Plenary, dates not examined; 32 A-B; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
        - Final Voting Plenary, dates not examined; 33 A-C; portion of 1 box (Box 2056)
      - Deprogramming, 1976; 1 box
        - "Faith and Mind Control" Dr. John Clark and Dr. David Allen, 1976; 1-2; portion of 1 box (Box 2057)
        - Radio Show with Galan Kelley on WFAS in Westchester, undated; 3; portion of 1 box (Box 2057)
  - Film, 1950 December 13-1983; 10 boxes
    - 16mm Film, 1952-1982; 7 boxes
      - NBC Today Show with John Chancellor, circa 1962; 1; portion of 1 box (Box 2058)
      - Cruel and Unjust Punishment, undated; 2; portion of 1 box (Box 2058)
      - Ira Glasser appearance on Phil Donahue, 1981; 3; 1 box (Box 2059)
      - "The Challenge", circa 1952; 4; portion of 1 box (Box 2060)
      - "Operation Abolition", 1960; 5; portion of 1 box (Box 2060)
      - "All-American", undated; 6; portion of 1 box (Box 2060)
      - "Operation Correction", 1960; 7; portion of 1 box (Box 2061)
      - "Fact Forum Panel with William Buckley, Patrick Malin, Richard Combs and Prof. Hodges, undated; 8; portion of 1 box (Box 2061)
      - "An Artist's Report", circa 1973; 9; portion of 1 box (Box 2062)
      - Donahue - Glasser and Moral Majority, 1982; 10; portion of 1 box (Box 2062)
      - Howe Case Exhibit Films, undated; 11; 1 box (Box 2063)
      - Howe Case Exhibit Films, undated; 12; 2 reels (Box 2064)
      - Unidentified, undated; 13; portion of 1 box (Box 2064)
    - Beta Video Cassettes, 1978 November 28-1983; 1 box
      - ACLU Public Service Announcements, 1978 November 28; 1; portion of 1 box (Box 2065)
      - This Week With David Brinkley; Capital Punishment, 1983 October 09; 2; portion of 1 box (Box 2065)
      - Texas Criminal Defense Lawyers Association; Death Penalty Litigation Conference, 1983; 3; portion of 1 box (Box 2065)
    - 33 1/3 rpm and 45 rpm Records, 1950 December 13-1976; 1 box
      - Friday is a Great Day, 1950 December 13; 1; 2 records) (33 1/3 rpm) (Box 2066)
      - Civil Liberties - Educational Audio Visual, 1976; 2; 3 records) (33 1/3 rpm) (Box 2066)
      - For the Dignity of Man; A Salute to Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965; 3; 45 rpm (Box 2066)
    - Microfilm, dates not examined; 1 box
      - ACLU Press Release and Testimony of L. Speiser, undated; 1; portion of 1 box (Box 2067)
      - "Pressure For Freedom: The ACLU" Barton Bean, undated; 2-3; portion of 1 box (Box 2067)
  - Photographs, 1930-1979; 9 boxes
    - Assembly and Public Protest - Paul Robeson Peekskill Riots, 1949; 24 photos (Box 2068)
    - Biennial Conference, 1964; 23 photos (Box 2068)
      Information on back of photos and negatives included.
    - Biennial Conference, 1966; 28 photos (Box 2069)
      Negatives included.
    - Biennial Conference, 1979; 14 photos (Box 2069)
    - Clerical Staff, 1930s; 1 photo (Box 2069)
    - Censorship - Ellis Post Office censorship case, 1949 April 29; 1 photo (Box 2070)
      Ellis holding box.
    - Censorship - "Flex-O-View" with viewer, 1950; 5 slides (Box 2070)
    - Censorship - "Desert Dancer", circa 1955; 1 slide (Box 2070)
    - Church/State - Scene from the Martin Luther motion picture, 1957; 1 photo (Box 2070)
    - Church/State - Rev. Liston Park, Snakehandler, Newport, IN, 1973; 2 photos (Box 2070)
    - Civil Rights Marches, dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2070)
    - Freedom to Movement - Kani Abdul Hamid Nouri upon his release, 1951; 2 photos (Box 2070)
    - Freedom of Movement - Ryszard Eibel, 1958; 5 photos (Box 2070)
    - International Civil Liberties - Yamazate-ku, Koza, 1956; 1 photo (Box 2070)
    - Portraits, dates not examined; portion of 6 boxes
      - Adams, Ruth, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2070)
      - Angell, Ernest, dates not examined; 7 photos (Box 2070)
      - Baldwin, Roger, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2070)
      - Baldwin, Roger, dates not examined; 3 photos
        - "Lively Libertarian", dates not examined; 8 photos (Box 2071)
        - 50th Birthday UPI photo, dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2071)
        - Proofs, dates not examined; 8 photos (Box 2071)
        - Negatives, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2071)
      - Biddle, Francis, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2071)
      - Bierstadt, Robert, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2071)
      - Black, Algernon David, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2071)
      - Block, Herbert L., dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2071)
      - Brown, Ralph S., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2071)
      - Burba, Elizabeth, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2071)
      - Portraits - Chaffe, Zecariah, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Clark, Ramsey, dates not examined; 4 photos (Box 2072)
      - Davidson, Dorothy, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - DeSilver, Albert, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Dobie, Frank, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Emerson, Thomas, dates not examined; 4 photos (Box 2072)
      - Ennis, Edward J., dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2072)
      - Ernst, Morris, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2072)
      - Evans, Luther, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Ferman, Irving, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Fly, James Lawrence, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Fraenkel, Osmond, dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2072)
      - Garbus, Martin, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Garrison, Lloyd K., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Gellhorn, Walter, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Gunther, John, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Hacker, Louis, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Harris, Patricia, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2072)
      - Hays, Arthur Garfield, dates not examined; 6 photos (Box 2072)
      - Heckscher, August, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Hendel, Samuel, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Holmes, John Haynes, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Horne, Dr. Frank S., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Huebsch, Benjamin, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2073)
      - Jacobs, Mrs. Yarnell, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Jones, Dr. John Paul, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Karpatkin, Marvin, dates not examined; 8 photos (Box 2073)
      - Kenyon, Judge Dorothy, dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2073)
      - Kerney Jr., James, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - McKay, Robert B., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - McNaughton, A.B., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Mazey, Ernest, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2073)
      - Malin, Patrick Murphy, dates not examined; 9 photos (Box 2073)
      - Maslow, Will, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Meiklejohn, Alexander, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Meserve, Harry, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Metzenbaum, Howard M., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Miller, Byron S., dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Miller, Reverend Edward, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Miller, Jay, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Millis, Walter, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Milner, Lucille, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2074)
      - Moore, William, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Morgan, Charles, dates not examined; 6 photos (Box 2074)
      - Neier, Aryeh, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2074)
      - Nelles, Walter, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Norton, Eleanor Holmes, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2074)
      - Parsons, Reverend Edward, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2074)
      - Pemberton, Jr., John de J., dates not examined; 10 photos (Box 2074)
      - Pilpel, Harriet, dates not examined; 3 photos (Box 2075)
      - Pinkus, Craig, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Pitkin, Wolcott, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Pratt, Elliot, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Redfield, Emanuel, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Reitman, Alan, dates not examined; 5 photos (Box 2075)
      - Rice, Elmer, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
      - Ross, William, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Rubin, Steve (with bombed out car), dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Schroeter, Leonard, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Schwartzschild, Henry, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
      - Slaff, George, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Speiser, Lawrence, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
      - Stevenson, Adlai, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
      - Stokes, Helen, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Strickland, Ann, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Ten Eyck, Barent, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
      - Tydings, Senator Joseph, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Wechsler, James, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Whiteside, Howard, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Williams, Edward Bennett, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Wood, L. Hollingsworth, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2075)
      - Wulf, Mel, dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2075)
    - Group Photos, 1963; 1 box
      - R. Baldwin, M. Tree, A. Macleish 12/3, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2076)
      - R. Baldwin, J. Pemberton, P. Malin, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2076)
      - R. Baldwin, A. Schlesinger, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2076)
      - P. Malin, A. Hays, G.W. Waring, E. Angell, dates not examined; 1 photo (Box 2076)
      - J. Pemberton, unidentified, 1963; 1 photo (Box 2076)
      - S. Teller, C. Darrow, Brophy, (12/28), dates not examined; 2 photos (Box 2076)
      - A. Hays (plus negative), dates not examined; portion of 1 box (Box 2076)
  - Professional Video Tape, 1970-1979; 9 boxes
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 1; 1 box (Box 2077)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 2; 1 box (Box 2078)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 3; 1 box (Box 2079)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 4; 1 box (Box 2080)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 5; 1 box (Box 2081)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 6; 1 box (Box 2082)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 7; 1 box (Box 2083)
    - The Rights of Americans, 1976; 8; 1 box (Box 2084)
    - Amnesty Spots, 1970s; 1 box (Box 2085)
  - Microfiche, 1980; 1 box
    - Microfiche, index cards, and program guide for Microsources "The Bill of Rights in the 20th Century," an instructional collection of primary source material, 1980; 1 box (Box 2085A)
  - Oversized Materials, 1931-1992; 18 boxes, 1 folder
    - ACLU Printed Materials, 1931-1992; 11 boxes
      - Civil Liberties, 1931-1992; 3 boxes (Box 2086, Box 2087, Box 2088)
      - Affiliate Publications, undated; 6 boxes (Box 2089, Box 2090, Box 2091, Box 2092, Box 2093, Box 2094)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 boxes (Box 2095, Box 2096)
    - Subject Files, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      Printed Material culled from Series 2, Project Files and Series 3, Subject Files includes:
      - Civil Rights, Government, International Civil Liberties, Labor and Business, Mass Communications, and Mental Health Issues, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 2097)
      - Military Rights (Amnesty Project) and Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 2098)
      - Native Americans and Women's Rights, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 2099)
    - Outside Organizations, dates not examined; 4 boxes
      - AFL-CIO News - Clarion, undated; 1 box (Box 2100)
      - Civil Rights News - Just Us, undated; 1 box (Box 2101)
      - Lancaster Independent - Quash, undated; 1 box (Box 2102)
      - Rights - Miscellaneous pamphlets and posters, undated; 1 box (Box 2103)
    - Posters, 1969; undated; 1 cabinets, 1 drawers (Folder Oversize folder 1, Cabinet 1, Drawer 13)
      Includes: 1) Lesbian and Gay Rights Project poster; 2) "Owners of the War Machine are the Real Criminals" (Chicago); 3) 1969 reprint from The Advance: "Dissent: The Basic Right of a Free People."